Guide to the The University of Montana Department of Native American Studies Records 1921-2003
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Subject Files, 1921-2003; Series I; 11.5 linear feet
  - Miscellaneous, Subseries 5
    - Montana's Seminar on Repatriation, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 12/13)
    - MUS (Montana University System) Ellen Swaney, 1990 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness Environmental Statement, 1976 (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Skyline Yarding System and Skyline Logging Symposium Proceedings, 1965 and 1969 (Box-folder 12/16)
    - Skyline Tension & Deflection Handbook, 1967 and 1970 (Box-folder 12/17)
    - Alcatraz Proclamation, 1969 (Box-folder 12/20)
    - In-Service Training Paper As it relates to Native Americans by Henrietta Whiteman, 1975 (Box-folder 12/22)
    - A vision: The warrior-scholar-community activist, The end product of Indian Studies, undated (Box-folder 13/6)
    - B.Y.U., 1975 and undated (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Sun Valley Presentation, Native American thought and the future of America: A Cross cultural Dialogue, 1975 (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Oklahoma Lectures, 1967 and 1969 (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Columbus Day Address, 1973 (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Henrietta Whiteman's Publications, 1972-1978 and undated (Box-folder 13/13)
    - University of Alaska, Fairbanks, 1985 (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Cultural Newspaper Clippings, 1976-1977 and undated (Box-folder 13/15)
    - Native American Definitions by Ed McGaa J.D., Oglala Sioux, undated (Box-folder 13/16)
    - Native Americans as Citizens, 1971 and undated (Box-folder 13/17)
    - National Council on Indian Opportunity, 1970 (Box-folder 13/18)
    - Ojo de Dios, undated (Box-folder 13/19)
    - Papers on Indian Historiography, 1975 (Box-folder 13/20)
    - A Policy for the Future, undated (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Prayer of an American Indian, By Philip Beaumont, Sr., undated (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Proud To be American?, Reprinted from University of Oklahoma Student paper, 1971 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Relocation, a history, undated (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Source Directory Indian Arts/Crafts Board for Native American Owned/Operated Arts/Crafts Businesses, 1978 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Suddenly Subject to new laws By Ed McGaa, undated (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Neighborhood Energy; Designing for Democracy; Designing for Democracy in the 1980s, 1978 (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Qua-Qui Indian Center, Missoula Montana Annual Report Fiscal Year, 1975 (Box-folder 14/12)
    - Selway-Bitterroot Management Plan, 1975 (Box-folder 14/17)
    - What do power Lines Transmit Besides Power, 1978 (Box-folder 14/18)
    - Petty Mountain Multiple Use Plan, Environmental Statement Draft, 1975 (Box-folder 14/19)
    - Montana Wilderness Association vs. Board Health, Answer to Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1975 (Box-folder 14/22)
    - A Native American Approach to Environmental Awareness, 1975 (Box-folder 14/24)
    - Understanding Indian People, What is your Indian I.Q.?, undated (Box-folder 15/3)
    - American Indian History Overview for the Indian Culture Master Plan, 1977 (Box-folder 15/18)
    - Rules and regulations, Acceptance of Tribal plans for operation of Bureau Programs, 1975 (Box-folder 15/27)
    - Proposal Writing Sources of Information and Possible Funding, undated (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Program Needs Assessment Survey, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 16/8)
    - White Philanthropy and the Red Man: No more gifts and promises, 1973 (Box-folder 16/10)
    - The arrival of the White Man by E. BigHorn, Brockton, undated (Box-folder 16/11)
    - What is an Indian Reservation?, undated (Box-folder 16/13)
    - What is an Indian?, U.S. Census definition, undated (Box-folder 16/14)
    - Was the truth buried at Wounded Knee? by Neil Hickey, undated (Box-folder 16/15)
    - "Voice from behind the buckskin curtain", 2 Papers presented at American Psychological Association, 1971 and 1975 (Box-folder 16/16)
    - Wa-Ne-Inee-Git Newsletter, undated (Box-folder 16/17)
    - "Urban Genocide: The Indian in the City", undated (Box-folder 16/18)
    - Trail Of Broken Treaties-20 Points, 1972 (Box-folder 16/19)
    - Summary of Recommendations and Associated Findings, undated (Box-folder 16/22)
    - The Writing of Project and Proposals: Accountability, undated (Box-folder 16/29)
    - Alcohol Legalization and Selected Sociological Variables among several Native American Tribes, undated (Box-folder 16/35)
    - Ethnic Differences In Babies, 1979 (Box-folder 16/36)
    - Distribution of Health Manpower, An Annotated Bibliography, 1973 (Box-folder 16/37)
    - Experimental Minority Recruitment Satellite Project, 1977 (Box-folder 16/38)
    - Fact sheets on Indians in health career, Statistics & objectives, 1974 (Box-folder 16/39)
    - Drugs, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - PL 94-984: Fact Sheet, 1976 (Box-folder 17/2)
    - American Journal of Public Health, Absentee Health Workers, 1972 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Food Rights and Nutrition, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - The First Americans, Report on Indian Health Program, 1976 (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Global Hunger, Inventory of Courses and Related Services UM, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 17/9)
    - Health News and Notes, Indian Health Board, Portland OR, 1981 (Box-folder 17/15)
    - Health Resources News, News Letters, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 17/16)
    - Incidence Of Mental Diseases on Indian Population, 1974 (Box-folder 17/17)
    - Montana State Plan for Social Services, Social Services Amendments, 1974 (Box-folder 17/20)
    - Social and Rehabilitation Services State of Montana, Regarding Progress of developmental Disabilities Program, 1975 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - War on Poverty, Community Action Program, undated (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Social sciences, The Bobbs-Merrill reprint series, 1938-1949 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - State Indian Coordinator's office, 1980 and 1991 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Computers, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Nutrition, Northwest Portland Area Indian Health Board, undated (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Health News and Notes, Indian Health Board, Portland OR, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Pre-Health Retention Information, 1977 (Box-folder 18/9)
    - Criminal Arraignment, Tribal Court, 1980 (Box-folder 18/11)
    - Private Foundation Directory, undated (Box-folder 18/13)
    - Native Americans & Poor Health Care Fact Sheet, undated (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Pre-Medical Information, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Research Priorities for Diseases of American Indians, 1974 (Box-folder 19/5)
    - Strategies for Restructuring Youth Services, The State Department of Youth Services, undated (Box-folder 19/6)
    - Veterans Administration, 1970 (Box-folder 19/8)
    - State Civil Power Over Reservation Indians by John F. Sullivan, undated (Box-folder 19/10)
    - Proposal: YWCA to the National Endowment for Humanities, 1980 (Box-folder 20/13)
    - Task Force Report, Appeal of APRC (Academic Program Review and Planning Committee, 1977 (Box-folder 20/14)
    - Proposal Review Committee, Budget Notes, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20/15)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Summer Stipends Program, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20/16)
    - Racism and Mental Health Grants, Division of Special Mental Health Programs, 1978 (Box-folder 20/17)
    - Proposal Review Committee with Tom Brown, Abstract-Ethnic Heritage Program, undated (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Grants Available, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Proposal Review Committee with Gary Kimble, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 21/3)
    - Iktomi, Story on spider, undated (Box-folder 21/8)
    - Indian Awareness Inventory Questionnaire undated (Box-folder 21/9)
    - Indian Definitions by Ed McGaa J.D. Oglala Sioux, undated (Box-folder 21/10)
    - ASCRC (Academic Standards and Curriculum Review Committee), 1985-1988 (Box-folder 22/1)
    - Cultural Materials, undated (Box-folder 22/4)
    - The Defenders, From Peacepipe To Tomahawk, undated (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Did you hear him?, Poem by Charlene Bearcub, 1972 (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Division of Native American Culture, undated (Box-folder 22/7)
    - Red Jacket's Reply to Missionary Cram, undated (Box-folder 22/9)
    - The Teachings of Don Juan by Carlos Castaneda, 1965 (Box-folder 22/14)
    - American Indian Authors by Tribe, undated (Box-folder 22/15)
    - Indian Arts & Crafts Board, Department of Interior Source Directory, 1976 (Box-folder 22/16)
    - Buckskin Collection, Check-out Book, 1979 (Box-folder 22/17)
    - Regional American Indian Policy Center, 1991 (Box-folder 22/18)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 22/19)
    - Diversity Report from George Dennison, 1997 (Box-folder 22/20)
    - Indian Preference Statutes, undated (Box-folder 23/2)
    - American Indian Children Foster Care Decision by Charlotte Goodluck and Mary Ellen Brown, undated (Box-folder 23/4)
    - Initials frequently used in Indian circles, undated (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Bad Day at Black Mesa, Los Angeles vs. The Indians II, 1971 (Box-folder 23/14)
    - Is It Always Right to Be Right?, undated (Box-folder 23/15)
    - The Indian Heritage of America by Alvin M. Josephy, Jr., undated (Box-folder 23/17)
    - Indians and Other Americans An Image of the Native American by David Stewart, 1971 (Box-folder 23/18)
    - The Legend of the Sacred Black Hills, undated (Box-folder 23/19)
    - Of National Prominence, undated (Box-folder 23/20)
    - Native American Consultant List, undated (Box-folder 23/21)
    - Poems by Ray Young Bear, undated (Box-folder 23/22)
    - Prayer of an American Indian, undated (Box-folder 23/23)
    - The Native American, American Studies & The Contemporary World, 1973 (Box-folder 23/24)
    - Pride in Heritage, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 23/25)
    - Proud To Be An American? By David N. Poolaw, 1971 (Box-folder 23/26)
    - Recovery of a Heritage, 1978 (Box-folder 23/27)
    - Reservation Indian, undated (Box-folder 23/28)
    - James West Sermon, 1972 (Box-folder 23/30)
    - Some Thoughts About the Bureau of Indian Affairs, undated (Box-folder 23/31)
    - United Native Americans Buy The State of Montana, undated (Box-folder 23/33)
    - Yu Wi Pi by Jonas Belt, undated (Box-folder 23/34)
    - Racial Equality, The future?, undated (Box-folder 23/38)
    - What does a Congressional Committee person do? Panel on "Working with Capital Hill", 1975 (Box-folder 24/2)
    - When, Poem by Charlene Bearcub, 1972 (Box-folder 24/3)
    - Yvonne Is Free, Yvonne Wanrow Defense committee, 1979 (Box-folder 24/4)
    - Proceedings on Discrimination Indians in Montana, 1979 (Box-folder 24/5)
    - Affirmation Of Sovereignty Of Indigenous People of the Western Hemisphere, 1978 (Box-folder 24/6)
    - Board of County Commissioners, County Taxpayers cannot assume federal and state program costs, 1976 (Box-folder 24/10)
    - Special Services for Disadvantaged Students, 1978 (Box-folder 24/14)
    - Appropriations Report 1975-77 Biennium, Office of Legislative Fiscal Analyst (Box-folder 24/15)
    - Department of the Interior Organizational Structure, 1970 (Box-folder 24/16)
    - Department of the Interior Letters, 1921 and 1923 (Box-folder 24/17)
    - Bureau Of Indian Affairs Area Offices, Agencies and other field Units, undated (Box-folder 24/19)
    - Resolution Opposing Repeal of Indian studies law, 1970 (Box-folder 24/20)
    - Crime Control and Native Americans, Adult, Juvenile Misdemeanor Arrests by race and offense, 1975 and 1976 (Box-folder 24/24)
    - Extermination Lecture, Quotes from Montana Post, 1864-1865 (Box-folder 24/26)
    - History of the Kyi-Yo Indian Club, 1985 (Box-folder 24/32)
    - Americans for Indian Opportunity, 1992 (Box-folder 25/1)
    - International Ecumenical Mission Consultation, 1992 (Box-folder 25/2)
    - Problem of Indian Administration, Johns Hopkins Press, 1928 (Box-folder 25/14)
    - Indian Concerns Sunday, 1983 (Box-folder 25/17)
    - Sweat Lodge Floor Plan, undated (Box-folder 25/20)
    - Boil and Hammer Are Living There, Told in English by Charley Anderson, 1954 (Box-folder 25/27)
    - Twin Light Trail Native American Indian News, undated (Box-folder 25/28)
    - Third Force Issues & Actions in Communities of Color, 1993 (Box-folder 25/31)
    - American Indians, Blacks, Chicanos, and Puerto Ricans, Journal of the American Academy of Arts & Sciences, 1981 (Box-folder 25/32)
- Department Records, 1977-1997; Series II; 1.0 linear foot
  - 5th NAS Forum Carrol College, 1997 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - 5th NAS Articulation Symposium, 1997 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - NAS Faculty Retreat, Agenda Topics, 1997 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - General Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - List of Native American Students, 1997 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - NAS Discussion Questions to consider in classes/seminars, undated (Box-folder 8/15)
  - NAS Buckskin Collection, 1980 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Anthropology 585, undated (Box-folder 10/4)
  - UM Sweat lodge at Ft. Missoula, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 10/24)
  - A philosophy of Native American Studies, 1978 (Box-folder 14/1)
  - NAS Newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14/21)
  - NAS Proposal Review Committee, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19/19)
  - NAS 100 Indian Culture Expressed as Language, Cheyenne Sacred Terminology, Fall 1988, undated (Box-folder 25/4)
  - NAS 100 Indian Culture Expressed as Language, The 4 Sacred Persons, Fall 1988, undated (Box-folder 25/5)
  - NAS 100 Indian Culture Expressed as Language, Pronunciation Guide, undated (Box-folder 25/6)
  - NAS 100 Indian Culture Expressed as Language, Cheyenne Life Journey, Fall 1988, undated (Box-folder 25/7)
  - NAS 100 Indian Culture Expressed as Language, Cheyenne Seasons of Human Development, Fall 1988, undated (Box-folder 25/8)
  - NAS 300 Model School Project, Spring 1988, undated (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Native American Studies Program Reports and Statements, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 25/34)